<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-17T11:43:03+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/</id><title type="html">σκέψη</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">baby steps</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/baby-steps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="baby steps" /><published>2018-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/baby-steps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/baby-steps/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://craigmod.com/essays/how_i_got_my_attention_back/&quot;&gt;getting your attention back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In “Gravity and Grace,” Simone Weil writes, “Attention, taken to its highest degree, is the same thing as prayer. It presupposes faith and love.” Then is the lack of attention the opposite? Does it presuppose fear and hate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;made &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/ngc3MS6yAqs&quot;&gt;a list of small pilgrim places&lt;/a&gt; on google&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;interview with &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;young dirty bastard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m rapping cause I’m hungry and my father’s not here and they don’t want me doing this. I’m only doing it because I wanna be on stage, and my mother wants me on stage, she’d kick my ass if I wasn’t. We need every nickel and dime. Shit, we might get kicked out of the house right now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We always had food stamps, food stamps is what we need. Some people don’t need em. But if food stamps weren’t there, I couldn’t be rapping. I gotta provide for my family. Babies gotta eat, G. It’s real. That’s how I’m standing, my momma fed me. We need food stamps, Government! Fuck Republicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;story for change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[…] tackling problems like climate change, inequality, and health care requires a systems approach. The work of systems change involves seeing systemically—looking at the elements, interconnections, and wider purposes of systems—and acting systemically. Story plays a vital role in helping us do both of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Story has many different qualities that make it useful for the work of systems change. It’s a direct route to our emotions, and therefore important to decision-making. It creates meaning out of patterns. It coheres communities. It engenders empathy across difference. It enables the possible to feel probable in ways our rational minds can’t comprehend. When it comes to changing the values, mindsets, rules, and goals of a system, story is foundational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one thing to remeber in this story as light, story as glue, story as web is that these same tools can (and are) used all the time for detrimental purposes, to alter oppressive narratives to adapt to new alternatives. narratives are only positive if they are conversations, not lectures…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ssir.org/articles/entry/solving_the_worlds_biggest_problems_better_philanthropy_through_systems_cha&quot;&gt;systems thinking for large-scale change:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Think in systems. Having a great idea for solving a social problem is just the beginning. You also need to identify the collaborators who can help you translate your innovation into real solutions for the real world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Engage in research and analysis to hone your strategy. Figure out what’s really needed—and what works.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Understand that effective communication is the lifeblood of any systems change campaign. Maintain transparent and compelling communications both internally with collaborative partners, and externally with public audiences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Embrace your inner policy wonk—and your inner politico. If you seek to change a complex system, you will often need to change the laws, administrative rules, and official practices governing that system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Measure and evaluate. Then measure and evaluate again. The most successful systems change campaigns create consistent and ongoing data assessments, and rely upon those findings to guide strategy and ensure accountability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">getting your attention back</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">critical consciousness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/critical-consciousness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="critical consciousness" /><published>2018-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/critical-consciousness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/critical-consciousness/">&lt;p&gt;i went for &lt;a href=&quot;https://walkofwisdom.org/2018/onze-eerste-pelgrims-uit-amerika/&quot;&gt;a walk in holland&lt;/a&gt; and i hope to go on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2016/apr/02/england-coast-path-2020-norfolk-walking-holidays&quot;&gt;2800 mile walk&lt;/a&gt; in england soon… i realized on my walk that walking is so fundamentally human that to leave it out of our rituals is to deprive ourselves of our selves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/04/02/the-mind-expanding-ideas-of-andy-clark&quot;&gt;the mind-expanding ideas of andy clark&lt;/a&gt; – connecting brains to environments, technology, and other brains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can buy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blueplaque.com/&quot;&gt;your very own blue plaque&lt;/a&gt; to put outside your flat and be famous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/espn/feature/story/_/id/23002739/82-flavors-russell-westbrook-every-outfit-oklahoma-city-thunder-star-wore-2017-18&quot;&gt;the best dressed man in the NBA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a talk by &lt;a href=&quot;glennadamson.com&quot;&gt;glenn adamson&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glennadamson.com/work/2017/8/2/complexitycomplex&quot;&gt;complexity complex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’m thinking about communalism and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milk_kinship&quot;&gt;milk kinship&lt;/a&gt; is a fascinating example of the embodied politic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Noble offspring were often sent to milk kin fosterers that would foster them to maturity so that the children would be raised by their successive status subordinates. The purpose of this was for political importance to build milk kin as bodyguards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2017/06/corporate-mentorship-programs/528927/&quot;&gt;why doesn’t mentoring work?&lt;/a&gt; from the atlantic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are many problems with the existing model of corporate mentorship, says Jennifer Labin, the principal partner of TERP Associates, a firm that specializes in creating public- and private-sector mentoring programs. “Mentoring programs have become this band-aid,” Labin says. She adds that, in her experience, programs are often “thrown together by overworked, overwhelmed people who’ve never built mentoring programs.” Many people in these roles have often never even been mentored themselves, according to Labin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the book Intelligent Mentoring, by Audrey Murrell, Sheila Forte-Trammel, and Diana Bing, the authors assert that the more traditional approach to mentoring—in which an older (and often white and male) senior employee chooses a younger (and often white and male) protégé to take beneath his wing—is outdated. The main reason this is the case is that one-on-one mentoring was pioneered during a time when it was normal for people to stay in the same full-time job, at the same organization, for years—if not their entire career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Researchers have established that negative mentoring experiences caused more intense emotional and behavioral responses among employees compared to positive incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…it’s hard to fix mentoring programs if employers don’t ask for feedback and employees don’t tell them what’s wrong. And that may be the case in many places. When I reached out to a group of elite, professional women about their experiences with workplace-based mentoring, hardly anyone volunteered to share stories on the record, for fear of professional blowback. One woman simply wrote, “Try to avoid formal programs at all costs. Torture.” The key to creating better mentorship programs, Labin said, is to be more thoughtful in the planning stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kanye’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=myrXQebr488&quot;&gt;original beat tape&lt;/a&gt; and a song from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IF_8zQYw24w&quot;&gt;Drake’s Dad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;long read on &lt;a href=&quot;https://longreads.com/2018/03/27/the-death-row-book-club/&quot;&gt;the death row book club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">i went for a walk in holland and i hope to go on this 2800 mile walk in england soon… i realized on my walk that walking is so fundamentally human that to leave it out of our rituals is to deprive ourselves of our selves.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">fool’s errand</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/fools-errand/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="fool's errand" /><published>2018-04-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/fools-errand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/fools-errand/">&lt;p&gt;really thinking hard about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dark-mountain.net/about/manifesto/&quot;&gt;dark mountain manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. it’s almost a decade old but still unfortunately prescient:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… a simple fact which any historian could confirm: human civilisation is an intensely fragile construction. It is built on little more than belief: belief in the rightness of its values; belief in the strength of its system of law and order; belief in its currency; above all, perhaps, belief in its future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is the story of how that people will cope with the crumbling of their own myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Integrity is wholeness, the greatest beauty is / Organic wholeness, the wholeness of life and things, the divine beauty / of the universe. Love that, not man / Apart from that, or else you will share man’s pitiful confusions, / or drown in despair when his days darken.
– Robinson Jeffers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is not a rejection of our humanity — it is an affirmation of the wonder of what it means to be truly human. It is to accept the world for what it is and to make our home here, rather than dreaming of relocating to the stars, or existing in a Man-forged bubble and pretending to ourselves that there is nothing outside it to which we have any connection at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The big names of contemporary literature are equally at home in the fashionable quarters of London or New York, and their writing reflects the prejudices of the placeless, transnational elite to which they belong.The converse also applies. Those voices which tell other stories tend to be rooted in a sense of place. Think of John Berger’s novels and essays from the Haute Savoie, or the depths explored by Alan Garner within a day’s walk of his birthplace in Cheshire. Think of Wendell Berry or WS Merwin, Mary Oliver or Cormac McCarthy. Those whose writings approach the shores of the Uncivilised are those who know their place, in the physical sense, and who remain wary of the siren cries of metrovincial fashion and civilised excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;nutrifluff&lt;/em&gt; is my new favorite word: nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2018/mar/25/chocolate-the-dark-truth-is-it-good-for-you-health-wellbeing-blood-pressure-flavanols&quot;&gt;Guardian article about chocolate&lt;/a&gt; that holds a larger message about the fragility of science and marketing. especially meta since this one word, ‘nutrifluff’, was picked up by dozens of online news-hawkers…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/22/t-magazine/art/artist-day-job.html&quot;&gt;artists and their day jobs&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It is not two jobs at all… one rests the man when the other fatigues him.” – William Carlos Williams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(After all, who wants to spend all their time in one room, even if it belongs to them?) Sometimes the artist needs to turn off, to get out in the fray, to stop worrying over when her imagination’s pot will boil…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;don’t resist and urge, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/your-money/resistance-is-futile-to-change-habits-try-replacement-instead.html&quot;&gt;replace it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;newish movie &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/26/movies/the-square-review-elisabeth-moss.html?referrer=google_kp&quot;&gt;The Square&lt;/a&gt; got me thinking about attention and responsibility in relation to art&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-markoff-stewart-brand-whole-earth-catalog-20180328-story.html&quot;&gt;Whole Earth Catalog turns 50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://semsound.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;friend of mine made a cool poetry app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2013/jan/27/kraftwerk-most-influential-electronic-band-tate&quot;&gt;who is Kraftwerk?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakola.com/arts/jerry-seinfeld-comedian-award-2007&quot;&gt;a funny speech from jerry seinfeld about awards&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And I don’t want to give you the wrong impression. I don’t want you to think that I’m not honored by this, because I’m, I feel very, very honored, and it’s – but it’s just that awards are stupid. Every real estate office has some framed, five-diamond president’s award thing by the desk, every hotel check-in has some gold circle service thing; every car salesman is a platinum jubilee winner. It’s all a big jerk off. It is, the hotel sucks, the real estate person is stupid, and the only thing the car salesman is good at is ripping you off. And why? Because awards don’t mean a goddamn thing. It’s stupid, they’re all stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Turk&quot;&gt;history of the mechanical turk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://abstractions.nautil.us/article/290/the-simple-algorithm-that-ants-use-to-build-bridges&quot;&gt;how ants build bridges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new words:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tate.org.uk/art/art-terms/a/agit-prop&quot;&gt;agitprop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/aetiology&quot;&gt;aetiology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peccadillo&quot;&gt;peccadillo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">really thinking hard about the dark mountain manifesto. it’s almost a decade old but still unfortunately prescient:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">deep result: everything oscillates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/oscillations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="deep result: everything oscillates" /><published>2018-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/oscillations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/oscillations/">&lt;p&gt;start with a great &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mathematical_jargon#deep&quot;&gt;wiki list of mathematical jargon&lt;/a&gt;, where we find the concept of a “deep result” is explained. a deep result is one which requires “deeper” knowledge, certain latent structures, to prove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;an example of a deep result is the infinite number of primes, which led me to a prime plot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot; height: 200px; overflow: hidden&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/0a/Primes_-_distribution_-_up_to_19_primorial.png/800px-Primes_-_distribution_-_up_to_19_primorial.png&quot; alt=&quot;Drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which looks shockingly similar to a spike raster plot of neurons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://actionpotential.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/polychronization01.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;looking at control systems, I found a reference to an older feedback controller than &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centrifugal_governor&quot;&gt;Maxwell’s steam engine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cornelis_Drebbel#Works&quot;&gt;Cornelius Hebbel’s&lt;/a&gt; temperature-regulating oven for chicken egg incubation. i then found an &lt;strong&gt;even&lt;/strong&gt; older version by the greek &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Water_clock#Greco-Roman_world&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;clepsydra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which means “water-thief”. feedback is used to correct the fact that a fuller pot will outflow from its bottom faster than a less full pot, due to the higher pressure at the outlet. the greeks even had alarms consisting of gongs attached to water clocks. bonkers. say thanks to poor &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ctesibius&quot;&gt;ctesibus&lt;/a&gt; for these wonderful inventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attending a royal society meeting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://royalsociety.org/science-events-and-lectures/2018/03/natural-systems/&quot;&gt;computation by natural systems&lt;/a&gt;, i was struck by an offhand comment at lunch (accompanied by a characteristic grin) by professor nick monk: “&lt;strong&gt;everything oscillates&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thinking about how the animal controls itself (weaning myself off of thinking about how to control the animal), a series of works by muraven and baumeister:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/buy/1998-01923-011&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/buy/1998-00299-017&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/docview/199849497?pq-origsite=gscholar&quot;&gt;1999&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2000-03444-003&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1467-8721.2007.00534.x&quot;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which all make the claim that cognitive regulation is a muscle that can be strengthened with deliberate effort. looking for normative results, i found a paper laboring towards a mechanistic understanding at this deliberate practice, a personal trainer for your mind-muscle, so to speak. the take-home from all of this work is inhibition; self-control or “executive function”, focused in the prefrontal cortex, is almost entirely negative feedback– inhibition is central to control. it’s what you &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; respond to that matters: attention is ignoring everything you deem unimportant. who decides what’s important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;speaking of oscillations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thing_(listening_device)&quot;&gt;a crazy story of a bug&lt;/a&gt; in the US ambassador’s office in Moscow in the 40s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i read &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_Bullshit&quot;&gt;harry frankfurt’s little book on bullshit&lt;/a&gt; a few years ago, but after hearing about james ladyman, i enjoyed his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=32ZaTKa2IRg&quot;&gt;frankfurt-inspired take on pseudoscience&lt;/a&gt; (warning: hour-long lecture)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my take aways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the ideal science should be self-correcting and aware of dogmatism and hubris (how much we know). appeals to epistemic authorities are necessary and relevant both politically and socially. scientific orthodoxy is the best way we have to generate facts and serve as such an authority. pseudoscience is not inherently non-science, fraud science, nor bad science. these non-science sciences must be properly defined for science-science to be held to task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brembs.net/learning/drosophila/foxp/&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; on operant conditioning vs language acquisition in the fly model… chomsky would not be amused. my take home is that this gene has something to do with different learning conditions, but the implications of “self-learning” and “world-learning” are interesting. that is, how is learning reinforced in light of “i did something” vs “my context was different”? perhaps they are one in the same. unclear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://computergraphics.stackexchange.com/questions/5085/light-intensity-of-an-rgb-value&quot;&gt;color is really complex, both physically and biologically&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a friend of mine just published &lt;a href=&quot;https://press.princeton.edu/titles/11108.html&quot;&gt;a spicy book about curves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;last but not least, a quote from lady gaga:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;you have to go to the broken place in your heart to write songs, like open heart surgery– it’s invasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">start with a great wiki list of mathematical jargon, where we find the concept of a “deep result” is explained. a deep result is one which requires “deeper” knowledge, certain latent structures, to prove.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">how you spend your time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/how-you-spend-your-time/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="how you spend your time" /><published>2018-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/how-you-spend-your-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/weeklies/how-you-spend-your-time/">&lt;p&gt;two aeon pieces that seem related: an incredible short doc about a horologist (which reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c08i_9gumJs&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; clip of Arvo Pärt), and a take on Martin Buber’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_and_Thou&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I and Thou&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. how can &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt; be loved? is there ever a time, so to speak, to break Buber’s commandment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/videos/finding-chaos-and-precision-in-all-things-a-philosophy-of-watchmaking&quot;&gt;chaos and precision in all things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/all-real-living-is-meeting-the-sacred-love-of-martin-buber&quot;&gt;the sacred love of martin buber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;speaking of things– a story of buildings and strength&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2018/feb/11/roma-agrawal-structural-engineers-are-unsung-heroes-interview-shard&quot;&gt;roma agrawal’s &lt;em&gt;Built&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the OJ trial is still overwhelming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1994/07/25/an-incendiary-defense&quot;&gt;jeffrey toobin’s 1994 &lt;em&gt;An Incendiary Defense&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what better story than a steamship full of refugee Soviet philosophers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philosophers%27_ships&quot;&gt;philosopher’s ships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there’s an inexplicable, visual beauty in the geometry and topology of music&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@lucas_gonze/coltrane-pitch-diagrams-e25b7d9f5093&quot;&gt;coltrane’s pitch diagrams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the relationship between wartime and technology never ceases to astound and frighten me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/1945/07/as-we-may-think/303881/&quot;&gt;as we may think, 1945&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vannevar_Bush&quot;&gt;vannevar bush&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;brushes, paints and the marks of self. bacon’s digestion/regurgitation of subjectivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MgrO5za0lSY&quot;&gt;a brush with violence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wonderful essay from Ramachandran about the self&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edge.org/conversation/self-awareness-the-last-frontier&quot;&gt;self: the last frontier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">two aeon pieces that seem related: an incredible short doc about a horologist (which reminds me of this clip of Arvo Pärt), and a take on Martin Buber’s I and Thou. how can things be loved? is there ever a time, so to speak, to break Buber’s commandment?</summary></entry></feed>