<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-08T15:21:44+01:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/</id><title type="html">σκέψη</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Week 2 PHIL2034</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/philosophy/PHIL2034-Week-2-Identity-Theory/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 2 PHIL2034" /><published>2018-05-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/philosophy/PHIL2034-Week-2-Identity-Theory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/philosophy/PHIL2034-Week-2-Identity-Theory/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-2&quot;&gt;Week 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identity Theory&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 2</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">social hope</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/social-hope/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="social hope" /><published>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/social-hope</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/social-hope/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Rorty&quot;&gt;Philosopher Richard Rorty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rorty tied this brand of philosophy to the notion of “social hope”; he believed that without the representationalist accounts, and without metaphors between the mind and the world, human society would behave more peacefully. He also emphasized the reasons why the interpretation of culture as conversation, constitutes the crucial concept of a “postphilosophical” culture determined to abandon representationalist accounts of traditional epistemology, incorporating American pragmatist naturalism that considers the natural sciences as an advance towards liberalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://money.stackexchange.com/questions/94671/why-isnt-everybody-rich&quot;&gt;why isn’t everybody rich?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Understand that you cannot duplicate your parent’s household immediately. It took them 20-30 years to get there. You are just starting out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Get out and stay out of consumer debt (this includes student loans and car payments)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Then start investing some money in low-cost mutual funds.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Save an emergency fund (3-6 months)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Buy a modest home (15-year mortgage 10-20% down)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;With any extra income: give some, spend some, and invest a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/21/opinion/sunday/the-real-cost-of-cheap-shirts.html&quot;&gt;nothing is cheap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if I want to buy something, which is often, I always put it on my list. After some time, I can decide if that thing will improve the quality of my life, and it is within my means to buy it. ‘within my means’ is a budgeting problem that’s in a process of constant revision. the important point here is that nothing is cheap– as with all relative transactions, what you include in your system of transaction matters. that’s not to argue naively for a zero-sum economic game, but perhaps there is some ethical conservation law…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i needed to extract text from a PDF file without indexed text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up finding a local solution using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;imagemagick&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tesseract&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;brew install tesseract, imagemagick&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;things didn’t work so i tried&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;brew install gs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which work. then taking the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;input.pdf&lt;/code&gt; file i &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;converted&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;imagemagick&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ convert -density 300 input.pdf -depth 8 -strip -background white -alpha off image_file.tiff&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where these &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;convert&lt;/code&gt; settings took a bit of trial and error. this tiff was &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;470MB&lt;/code&gt; for 53 pages of large text. using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tesseract&lt;/code&gt;, i made &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;output.txt&lt;/code&gt; with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ tesseract -l eng image_file.tif output&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2018/05/reinventing-america/556856/?single_page=true&quot;&gt;some optimism about America from the Atlantic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What we learned from traveling was not that the hardest American challenges of this era are illusory. They’re very real, and divisions about national politics are intense. So we made a point of never asking, early on, “How’s Obama doing?,” or later, “Do you trust Hillary?” and “What about Trump?” The answers to questions like those won’t take you beyond what you’ve already heard ad nauseam on TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Instead we asked people about their own lives and their own communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;very Freire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Rainmaker1973/status/988711358358261762&quot;&gt;cool pics from a comet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This is what a view on a comet looks like, among dust, stars and cosmic ray hits, as captured by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ESA_Rosetta?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ESA_Rosetta&lt;/a&gt; on June 1, 2016 and processed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/landru79?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@landru79&lt;/a&gt; from these raw data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/h3BV6Z2V71&quot;&gt;https://t.co/h3BV6Z2V71&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/w1Yv4OwIo1&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/w1Yv4OwIo1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Massimo (@Rainmaker1973) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Rainmaker1973/status/988711358358261762?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 24, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/vb.html&quot;&gt;life is too short for bullshit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Arguments of the form “Life is too short for x” have great force. It’s not just a figure of speech to say that life is too short for something. It’s not just a synonym for annoying. If you find yourself thinking that life is too short for something, you should try to eliminate it if you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;bullshit does have a distinctive character. There’s something fake about it. It’s the junk food of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cultivate a habit of impatience about the things you most want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The “flow” that imaginative people love so much has a darker cousin that prevents you from pausing to savor life amid the daily slurry of errands and alarms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Relentlessly prune bullshit, don’t wait to do things that matter, and savor the time you have. That’s what you do when life is short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2017/nov/25/chinas-bike-share-graveyard-a-monument-to-industrys-arrogance&quot;&gt;when capitalism kills good things like bicycles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c217fdc4f8ce3df1ae171ccfcda6e0e8007676dc/64_0_2666_1600/master/2666.jpg?w=860&amp;amp;q=20&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;dpr=2&amp;amp;s=05635ef64c53e356925e8fb3b87d92c1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/14/nyregion/david-buckel-dead-fire.html&quot;&gt;Buckel’s self-immolation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Privilege, he said, was derived from the suffering of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Many who drive their own lives to help others often realize that they do not change what causes the need for their help,” Mr. Buckel wrote, adding that donating to organizations was not enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By 11 a.m., the authorities had removed Mr. Buckel’s body, leaving a blackened patch and a circular indentation around which parks officials placed two orange cones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The grim scene stood in stark contrast to the rest of the park, which brimmed with activity. Several youth baseball games continued nearby and participants in PurpleStride, a walk dedicated to ending pancreatic cancer, strode along the bike path with runners and joggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Sapolsky&quot;&gt;Finding your baboons?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 1978, Sapolsky received his B.A. in biological anthropology summa cum laude from Harvard University.[8] He then went to Kenya to study the social behaviors of baboons in the wild; after which he returned to New York; studying at Rockefeller University, where he received his Ph.D. in neuroendocrinology working in the lab of endocrinologist Bruce McEwen.
Following Sapolsky’s initial year-and-a-half field study in Africa, he returned every summer for another twenty-five years to observe the same group of baboons, from the late 70s to the early 90s. He spent 8 to 10 hours a day for approximately four months each year recording the behaviors of these primates.[9]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i have this idea of &lt;em&gt;raw material&lt;/em&gt;. often (continental) philosophers use literature, poetry, and film as currency in arguments. language is borrowed from art as material to build rhetoric, to color examples. in the same way, scientists have raw material, they have experiences documenting the social habits of baboons, they have data from microscopes and sensors. we all have raw material in the way of experience. choosing experiences, making choices that lead to transformations in the world lead to changes in experience. what i am working to do is reflect on these experiences, use them as &lt;em&gt;raw material&lt;/em&gt; to craft new experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reflect on your baboons.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Philosopher Richard Rorty</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1 PHIL2034</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/philosophy/PHIL2034-Week-1-Rorty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1 PHIL2034" /><published>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/philosophy/PHIL2034-Week-1-Rorty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/philosophy/PHIL2034-Week-1-Rorty/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-1&quot;&gt;Week 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Invention of the Mind” (Rorty 1979)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;universals and particulars are cut as mental and physical&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wittgenstein— universals are contextual, within the language game&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;neural correlations could give us thoughts, mental images, etc
	the hard problems is the particular one— one are YOUR feelings like?
	to solve it is usually to create a bugbear– to swap brains, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;even if neural correlations didn’t work, why make immaterial things?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the ontological gap is actually an epistemic privilege problem 
	YOUR thoughts are incorrigible, undoubtable 
	(cool connection wth skepticism here, solipsism)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rorty tries to understand why we have a mind-body problem, tracing the “problem” through from the ancients to contemporary neo-dualist arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So when Ryle suggests that to talk of mental entities is to talk of dispositions to behave, or when Smart suggests that it is to talk of neural states, they have two strikes against them. For why, if anything like behaviorism or materialism is true, should there be anything like this intuitive distinction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein and Strawson that in some sense there is nothing there but the human organism, and that we must give up the notion of this organism as made out of a bit of &lt;em&gt;res cogitans&lt;/em&gt; nonspatially associated with a bit of &lt;em&gt;res extensa&lt;/em&gt;. But, they say, no scientiﬁc discovery can reveal an identity This intuition seems to them enough to establish an unbridgeable gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this situation, it is tempting for the dualist to go linguistic and begin talking about “different vocabularies” or “alternative descriptions.” [e.g. Spinoza’s double-aspect theory] The question “two descriptions of what?” makes this a difﬁcult position to hold onto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We have the following dilemma: either neo-dualists must construct an epistemological account of how we know a priori that entities fall under two irreducibly distinct ontological species, or else they must ﬁnd some way of expressing their dualism which relies on neither the notion of “ontological gap” nor that of “alternative description.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We feel vaguely conﬁdent that if the inﬁnite could exist, it, like the universal, could only be exempliﬁed by the immaterial. If it makes any sense to speak of the existence of universals, it would seem that they must exist immaterially, and that is why they can never be identiﬁed with spatio—temporal particulars. […] Nevertheless the opposite of “mental” is “physical” and the opposite of “immaterial” is “material.” “Physical” and “material” seem synonymous. How can two distinct concepts have synonymous opposites?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is spatiotemporal? Why is it useful? What is a spatial or non-spatial state? Freeze time, we say, and they analyze the spatial structure, like in a photograph. But a photograph is dependent on time. It is useful only because of this time instant relative to other time instants, in a time-context. This might be what Deleuze is talking about with &lt;em&gt;movement-image&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;time-image&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are not entitled to begin talking about the mind-body problem, or about the possible identity or necessary non-identity of mental and physical states, without ﬁrst asking what we mean by “mental.” I would hope further to have incited the suspicion that our soocalled intuition about what is mental may be merely our readiness to fall in with a speciﬁcally philosophical language-game. I think that this socalled intuition is no more than the ability to command a certain technical vocabulary—one which has no use outside of philosophy books and which links up with no issues in daily life, empirical science, morals, or religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To say that we cannot observe intentional properties by looking at the brain is like saying that we cannot see a proposition when we look at a Mayan codex—we simply do not know what to look for, because we do not yet know how to relate what we see to a symbolsystem. The relation between an inscription—on paper or, given the hypothesized concomitance, in the brain—and what it means is no more mysterious than the relation between a functional state of a person, such as his beauty or his health, and the parts of his body. It is just those parts seen in a given context. So the answer to the question “Why is the intentional nonmaterial?” is “because any functional state—any state which can only be grasped by relating what is observed to a larger context—is, in a trivial sense, nonmaterial.” The problem is in trying to relate this trivial notion of being “nonmaterial”—which means merely something like “not immediately evident to all who look”—with the philosophically pregnant sense of “immateriality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To put it another way, why should we be troubled by Leibniz’s point that if the brain were blown up to the size of a factory, so that we could stroll through it, we should not see thoughts? If we know enough neural correlations, we shall indeed see thoughts—in the sense that our vision will reveal to us what thoughts the possessor of the brain is having. If we do not, we shall not, but then if we stroll through any factory without having ﬁrst learned about its parts and their relations to one another, we shall not see ‘what is going on. Further, even if we could ﬁnd no such neural correlations, even if cerebral localization of thoughts was a complete failure, why would we want to say that a person’s thoughts or mental images were nonphysical simply because we cannot give an account of them in terms of his parts? To use an example from Hilary Putnam, one cannot give an account of why square pegs do not ﬁt into round holes in terms of the elementary particles which constitute the peg and the hole, but nobody ﬁnds a perplexing ontological gap between macrostructure and microstructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why do some neo-dualist philosophers say that how something feels, what it is like to be something, cannot be identical with any physical property, or at least any physical property which we know anything about? A trivial answer to this question would be that we can know all about something’s physical properties and not know how it feels-—especially if we can’t talk to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why should this epistemic distinction reﬂect an ontological distinction? Why should the epistemic privilege we all have of being incorrigible about how things seem to us reﬂect a distinction between two realms of being? The answer presumably has to go something like this: Feelings just are appearances. Their reality is exhausted in how they seem. They are pure seemings. Anything that is not a seeming (putting the intentional to one side for the moment) is merely physical—that is, it is something which can appear other than it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are our intuitions wrong? Are we not always completely seeming, swimming through a pool of air and dust? Is the only pure state the ground state of quantum mechanics-the vacuum state? We cannot think in vacuum, can we? What is thought, belief, desire, love &lt;em&gt;in vacuo&lt;/em&gt;? Pain, the mental, being made of mind-stuff, or the forcing of argument to this point misunderstands what the mental is and is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The neo-dualist is no longer talking about how people feel but about feelings as little self-subsistent entities, ﬂoating free of people in the way in which universals ﬂoat free of the instantiations. He has, in fact, modeled pains on universals. It is no wonder, then, that he can “intuit” that pains can exist separately from the body, for this intuition is simply the intuition that universals can exist independently of particulars. […] To put it oxymoronically, mental particulars, unlike mental states of people, turn out to be universals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why do we think of the phenomenal as immaterial? We do so because, as Ryle put it, we insist on thinking of having a pain in ocular metaphors—as having a funny sort of par.ticular before the eye of the mind. That particular turns out to be a universal, a quality hypostatized into a subject of predication. Thus when neo-dualists say that how pains feel are essential to what pains are, and then criticize Smart for thinking of the causal role of certain neurons as what is essential to pain, they are changing the subject. Smart is talking about what is essential to people being in pain, whereas neo-dualists like Kripke are talking about what is essential for something’s being a pain. Neo-dualists feel unafraid of the question “What is the epistemological basis for your claim to know what is an essential property of pain?” for they have arranged things so that pains have only one intrinsic property—namely, feeling painful—and so the choice of which properties are to count as essential to them is obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The mental-physical distinction is parasitic on the universal-particular distinction. Further, the notion of mind-stuff as that out of which pains and beliefs are made makes exactly as much or as little sense as the notion of “that of which universals are made.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Following Wittgenstein, we shall treat the intentional as merely a subspecies of the functional, and the functional as merely the sort of property whose attribution depends upon a knowledge of context rather than being observable right off the bat. We shall see the intentional as having no connection with the phenomenal, and the phenomenal as a matter of how we talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just as the patient needs to relive his past to answer his questions, so philosophy needs to relive its past in order to answer its questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In my Wittgensteinian view, an intuition is never anything more or less than familiarity with a language—game, so to discover the source of our intuitions is to relive the history of the philosophical language-game we ﬁnd ourselves playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let us call the “problem of personhood” that of what more a human being is than ﬂesh. This problem has one form in the pre-philosophical craving for immortality, and another in the Kantian and romantic assertion of human dignity—but both cravings are quite distinct from problems about consciousness and about knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The problem of consciousness centers around the brain, raw feels, and bodily motions. The problem of reason centers around the topics of knowledge, language, and intelligence—all our “higher powers.” The problem of personhood centers around attributions of freedom and of moral responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Philosophy undertook to examine the difference between knowing that there were parallel mountain ranges to the west and knowing that inﬁnitely extended parallel lines never meet, the difference between knowing that Socrates was good and knowing what goodness was. So the question arose: What are the analogies between knowing about mountains and knowing about lines, between knowing Socrates and knowing the Good? When this question was answered in terms of the distinction between the eye of the body and the Eye of the Mind, νους–thought, intellect, insight—-was identiﬁed as what separates men from beasts. There was, we moderns may say with the ingratitude of hindsight, no particular reason why this ocular metaphor seized the imagination of the founders of Western thought. But it did, and contemporary philosophers are still working out its consequences, analyzing the problems it created, and asking whether there may not be something to it after all. The notion of “contemplation,” of knowledge of universal concepts or truths as θεωρία, makes the Eye of the Mind the inescapable model for the better sort of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;froghood  = skimming off the universal from the clearly known particular frog, so to speak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our Glassy Essence; It is glassy—mirror-like—for two reasons. First, it takes on new forms without being changed—but intellectual forms, rather than sensible ones as material mirrors do. Second, mirrors are made of a substance which is purer, ﬁner grained, more subtle, and more delicate than most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The image of our Glassy Essence remains with us, as does Isabella’s lament that we cannot grasp it. A sense of moral failure mixes with a sense of grievance that philosophy—the discipline supremely concerned with “the higher”—has not made us more aware of our own nature. That nature, it is still felt, makes its distinctive character most clearly felt in a certain sort of knowledge—knowledge of the highest and purest things: mathematics, philosophy itself, theoretical physics, anything which contemplates universals. To suggest that there are no universals—that they are ﬂatus vocis—is to endanger our uniqueness. To suggest that the mind is the brain is to suggest that we secrete theorems and symphonies as our spleen secretes dark humors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Aristotle’s conception intellect is not a mirror inspected by an inner eye. It is both mirror and eye in one. The retinal image is itself the model for the “intellect which becomes all things,” whereas in the Cartesian model, the intellect inspects entities modeled on retinal images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The difﬁculty is in ﬁnding a Greek equivalent for “sensation” in the sense philosophers make it bear. . . . “Sensation” was introduced into philosophy precisely to make it possible to speak of a conscious state without committing oneself as to the nature or even existence of external stimuli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Importantly, there had been no term, even of philosophical art, in the Greek and medieval traditions coextensive with the Descartes-Locke use of “idea.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Aristotle, the faculty which received universals without embodying them in matter was “separable” and it was hard (without some help from extra-philosophical concerns, such as Christianity) to say whether one should view it as 1) a special power which the body had, 2) a separate substance attached to each mature human body, or perhaps 3) a single substance which was somehow shared among as many men and angels as there happened to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Descartes will admit only three substances—thought, extension, and God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“argument from doubt:” what we can doubt exists cannot, by Leibniz’s law, be identical with what we cannot doubt exists. this argument is “universally recognized to be fallacious.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If I am right in thinking that Descartes’s badly argued hunch, the one which made him able to see pains and thoughts as modes of a single substance, was that indubitability was the common factor they shared with nothing physical, then we can see him as working his way around toward a view in which indubitability is no longer the mark of eternality, but rather of something for which the Greeks had no name—consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Cartesian change from mind-as-reason to mind-as-inner-arena was not the triumph of the prideful individual subject freed from scholastic shackles so much as the triumph of the quest for certainty over the quest for wisdom. From that time. forward, the way was open for philosophers either to attain the rigor of the mathematician or the mathematical physicist, or to explain the appearance of rigor in these ﬁelds, rather than to help people attain peace of mind. Science, rather than living, became philosophy’s subject, and epistemology its center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The notion which would deﬁne what could “have a distinct existence from the body” was one which would draw a line between the cramps in one’s stomach and the associated feeling in one’s mind. I have suggested that the only criterion which will draw this line is indubitability—that closeness to the Inner Eye which permits Descartes to say that “nothing is easier for the mind to know than itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It seems plausible to say that Descartes’s insight was merely a recognition of the difference between parts of persons or states of those parts (e.g., cramps of their stomachs) on the one hand and certain states of the whole person on the other, misleadingly stated in a corrupted scholastic vocabulary as a distinction of “substance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My answer to the question “Why do we tend to lump the intentional and the phenomenal together as ‘the mental’?” is that Descartes used the notion of the “incorrigibly known” to bridge the gap between them. So I now need to spell out more fully my own anti-Cartesian, Wittgensteinian, view of the nature of “our privileged access to the mental.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I shall try to show that the purportedly metaphysical “problem of consciousness” is no more and no less than the epistemological “problem of privileged access,” and that once this is seen questions about dualism versus materialism lose their interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refs: 
Richard Rorty, “Incorrigibility as the Mark of the Mental,” Journal of Philosophy 67 (1970), 406-409&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aristotle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘Hylomorphism’ is simply a compound word composed of the Greek terms for matter (hulê) and form or shape (morphê); thus one could equally describe Aristotle’s view of body and soul as an instance of his “matter-formism.” That is, when he introduces the soul as the form of the body, which in turn is said to be the matter of the soul, Aristotle treats soul-body relations as a special case of a more general relationship which obtains between the components of all generated compounds, natural or artifactual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;’’'’soul : body :: form : matter :: Hermes-shape : bronze’’’’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Aristotle thinks that Plato and other dualists are right to stress the importance of the soul in explanations of living beings. At the same time, he sees their commitment to the separability of the soul from the body as unjustified merely by appeal to formal causation: he will allow that the soul is distinct from the body, and is indeed the actuality of the body, but he sees that these concessions by themselves provide no grounds for supposing that the soul can exist without the body. His hylomorphism, then, embraces neither reductive materialism nor Platonic dualism. Instead, it seeks to steer a middle course between these alternatives by pointing out, implicitly, and rightly, that these are not exhaustive options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the one hand, he insists that because various psychological states, including anger, joy, courage, pity, loving, and hating, all involve the body in central and obvious ways, the study of soul “is already in the province of the natural scientist”. At the same time, however, he insists that the mind or intellect (nous) may not be enmeshed in the body in the same way as these sorts of states, and so denies that the study of soul falls in its entirety to the natural scientist. This is presumably why in the opening chapter of De Anima Aristotle reports a deep and authentic perplexity about the best method for investigating psychological matters. If different sciences employ different methods and the study of soul is bifurcated so that it belongs to no one science, there will indeed be a genuine difficulty about how best to proceed in any inquiry concerning it. It seems fair to say that these sorts of quandaries have not left us altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Wittgensteinian reformulation, the Hermes-shape is a Hermes-shape only in the context of our language game. If someone did not recognize Hermes, they might say “man-shape” in his stead, thus appealing to a more general game. Form embodies concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;’’'’S thinks O if and only if: (i) S has the capacity requisite for receiving O’s intelligible form; (ii) O acts upon that capacity by enforming it; and, as a result, (iii) S’s relevant capacity becomes isomorphic with that form.’’’’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the same questions which arose in the case of perception also arise here. Most immediately, to understand Aristotle’s approach to thinking, it is necessary to determine what it means to say that a thinker’s mind and its object become isomorphic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Week 1</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">why?</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/neuro/why/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="why?" /><published>2018-04-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/neuro/why</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/neuro/why/">&lt;p&gt;why study neuroscience? to move towards a hughter reason– to communicate something to pepole about themselves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not to psychoanalysis or linguistics but to the biology of the brain that we should look for principles, because it doesn’t have the drawback, like the other two disciplines, of drawing on ready-made concepts. We can consider the brain as a relatively undifferentiated mass and ask what circuits . . . the movement-image or the time-image trace out, or invent, because the circuits aren’t there to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Deleuze once famously described his method of interpreting philosophers as “buggery (enculage)”, as sneaking behind an author and producing an offspring which is recognizably his, yet also monstrous and different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Deleuze sharply distinguishes art, philosophy, and science as three distinct disciplines, each analyzing reality in different ways. While philosophy creates concepts, the arts create novel qualitative combinations of sensation and feeling (what Deleuze calls “percepts” and “affects”), and the sciences create quantitative theories based on fixed points of reference such as the speed of light or absolute zero (which Deleuze calls “functives”). According to Deleuze, none of these disciplines enjoy primacy over the others:[35] they are different ways of organizing the metaphysical flux, “separate melodic lines in constant interplay with one another.”[36] For example, Deleuze does not treat cinema as an art representing an external reality, but as an ontological practice that creates different ways of organizing movement and time.[37] Philosophy, science, and art are equally, and essentially, creative and practical. Hence, instead of asking traditional questions of identity such as “is it true?” or “what is it?”, Deleuze proposes that inquiries should be functional or practical: “what does it do?” or “how does it work?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Deleuze’s key ideas. There is, for example, his famous point that philosophy is the creation of concepts. Without the creation of new concepts, there can be no thinking with a difference, no line of flight in thought. Second, and closely related to this, Deleuze proposed that concepts are tools of analysis, not recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they still get stuck on duality
the main reason, and to me the most interesting reason, is that we cant let go of our mental vocabulary
because its not just semantic (i think) like “eliminative” materialists would say, they would eliminate that language in favor of “weakened feedback from cortex to basal ganglion 17” or whatever
so it feels cheap to me to say “it is us”
i mean it is! who could argue that
it’s about making an eloquent argument for why we have these words, and why we have commonalities
souls, thoughts, mental images, sadness
its as cheap to say “they dont exist &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;”
as it is to say “they just &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;”
but its not right to ask “&lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; are they”
i think it’s much more interesting/productive/fun to ask “&lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; are they”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what is pre-screen society? apart from metaphors, how has our experience changed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met two film students, they were excited to think that their form, as opposed to the scientific mode, was held in equal esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what questions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;how is the brain organized? how does the structure of the brain give rise to complex computations? 
how does the brain control itself, or how is it controlled by phenomena/sensation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my dream is to apply neural organizational principles to understanding how people/groups organize
like applying natural structure to human structure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this structure is the system– i’m worried because i don’t want to invest because it’s a system that perpetuates oppression and inequality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is the structure, this is the framework in which decisions are made. the anatomy of the brain is not static. it changes genetically, over evolutionary time scales, and the functional goings-on changes on many faster time scales of various length&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the differences between how and why and what in neuroscience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;how did google grow? first a tech, then decision to use ads&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;have to change how people think— metaphors and paradigms of thinking e.g. OO operating system? interacting objects with files, etc? each project is a module?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">why study neuroscience? to move towards a hughter reason– to communicate something to pepole about themselves</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">…and all that.</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/and-all-that/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="...and all that." /><published>2018-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/and-all-that</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/and-all-that/">&lt;p&gt;kendrick lamar wins &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/therecord/2018/04/16/602948758/kendrick-lamars-damn-wins-historic-pulitzer-prize-in-music&quot;&gt;the pulitzer for music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OFS1F_aktwo8tfoN3L1JiO_0kPI=/0x0:1000x1000/1200x800/filters:focal(416x29:576x189)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/59411025/ada232f9f870cf829171fa8990916aa9.1000x1000x1.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a confessional blog post about &lt;a href=&quot;https://craigmod.com/essays/how_i_got_my_attention_back/&quot;&gt;getting your attention back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In “Gravity and Grace,” Simone Weil writes, “Attention, taken to its highest degree, is the same thing as prayer. It presupposes faith and love.” Then is the lack of attention the opposite? Does it presuppose fear and hate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i made &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/ngc3MS6yAqs&quot;&gt;a list of small pilgrim places&lt;/a&gt; on google maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and an opposite type of space…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In shopping mall design, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gruen_transfer&quot;&gt;the Gruen transfer&lt;/a&gt; (also known as the Gruen effect) is the moment when consumers enter a shopping mall or store and, surrounded by an intentionally confusing layout, lose track of their original intentions, making consumers more susceptible to make impulse buys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelondonbookshopmap.org/&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; of independent book stores in london&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brights_movement&quot;&gt;a very problematic movement&lt;/a&gt; concerning secularism, religion, and language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GKd71Uyf3Mo&quot;&gt;interview with deleuze&lt;/a&gt;… my favorite &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/GKd71Uyf3Mo?t=479&quot;&gt;bit about art and science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jODDZpy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;...and all that&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;several landscape-themed artistic things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/the-turn-of-the-century-pigeons-that-photographed-earth-from-above&quot;&gt;early 20c aerial photography by pigeons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5ad0cf1e40fc7c73d8309ed7/master/w_4000,c_limit/0138001_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christo_and_Jeanne-Claude&quot;&gt;christo and jean-claude&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/66/A_SIX-TON_CURTAIN_BILLOWS_ACROSS_RIFLE_GAP_-_CONCEIVED_BY_ARTIST_CHRISTO_JAVACHEFF%2C_EXECUTED_AT_A_COST_OF_%24700%2C000...._-_NARA_-_544843.jpg/2560px-A_SIX-TON_CURTAIN_BILLOWS_ACROSS_RIFLE_GAP_-_CONCEIVED_BY_ARTIST_CHRISTO_JAVACHEFF%2C_EXECUTED_AT_A_COST_OF_%24700%2C000...._-_NARA_-_544843.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://visualmelt.com/Andy-Goldsworthy&quot;&gt;andy goldsworthy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://payload135.cargocollective.com/1/1/60195/5013893/art%20140_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://noisey.vice.com/en_uk/article/rgwz3r/meet-young-dirty-bastard-son-of-ol-dirty-bastard&quot;&gt;young dirty bastard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m rapping cause I’m hungry and my father’s not here and they don’t want me doing this. I’m only doing it because I wanna be on stage, and my mother wants me on stage, she’d kick my ass if I wasn’t. We need every nickel and dime. Shit, we might get kicked out of the house right now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We always had food stamps, food stamps is what we need. Some people don’t need em. But if food stamps weren’t there, I couldn’t be rapping. I gotta provide for my family. Babies gotta eat, G. It’s real. That’s how I’m standing, my momma fed me. We need food stamps, Government! Fuck Republicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ssir.org/articles/entry/using_story_to_change_systems&quot;&gt;story for change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[…] tackling problems like climate change, inequality, and health care requires a systems approach. The work of systems change involves seeing systemically—looking at the elements, interconnections, and wider purposes of systems—and acting systemically. Story plays a vital role in helping us do both of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Story has many different qualities that make it useful for the work of systems change. It’s a direct route to our emotions, and therefore important to decision-making. It creates meaning out of patterns. It coheres communities. It engenders empathy across difference. It enables the possible to feel probable in ways our rational minds can’t comprehend. When it comes to changing the values, mindsets, rules, and goals of a system, story is foundational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one thing to remember in this story as light, story as glue, story as web is that these same tools can (and are) used all the time for detrimental purposes, to alter oppressive narratives to adapt to new alternatives. narratives are only positive if they are conversations, not lectures…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Any large-scale human cooperation—whether a modern state, a medieval church, an ancient city or an archaic tribe—is rooted in common myths that only exist in people’s collective imagination.” &lt;br /&gt; -Yuval Noah Harari&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Change the personal narratives we have about our lives.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Change the cultural narratives that frame the issues we advocate for.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Change the mythic narratives that influence our worldview.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ssir.org/articles/entry/solving_the_worlds_biggest_problems_better_philanthropy_through_systems_cha&quot;&gt;systems thinking for large-scale change:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Think in systems. Having a great idea for solving a social problem is just the beginning. You also need to identify the collaborators who can help you translate your innovation into real solutions for the real world.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Engage in research and analysis to hone your strategy. Figure out what’s really needed—and what works.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Understand that effective communication is the lifeblood of any systems change campaign. Maintain transparent and compelling communications both internally with collaborative partners, and externally with public audiences.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Embrace your inner policy wonk—and your inner politico. If you seek to change a complex system, you will often need to change the laws, administrative rules, and official practices governing that system.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Measure and evaluate. Then measure and evaluate again. The most successful systems change campaigns create consistent and ongoing data assessments, and rely upon those findings to guide strategy and ensure accountability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">kendrick lamar wins the pulitzer for music</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">critical consciousness</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/critical-consciousness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="critical consciousness" /><published>2018-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/critical-consciousness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/critical-consciousness/">&lt;p&gt;i went for &lt;a href=&quot;https://walkofwisdom.org/2018/onze-eerste-pelgrims-uit-amerika/&quot;&gt;a walk in holland&lt;/a&gt; and i hope to go on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2016/apr/02/england-coast-path-2020-norfolk-walking-holidays&quot;&gt;2800 mile walk&lt;/a&gt; in england soon… i realized on my walk that walking is so fundamentally human that to leave it out of our rituals is to deprive ourselves of our selves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/04/02/the-mind-expanding-ideas-of-andy-clark&quot;&gt;the mind-expanding ideas of andy clark&lt;/a&gt; – connecting brains to environments, technology, and other brains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can buy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blueplaque.com/&quot;&gt;your very own blue plaque&lt;/a&gt; to put outside your flat and be famous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/espn/feature/story/_/id/23002739/82-flavors-russell-westbrook-every-outfit-oklahoma-city-thunder-star-wore-2017-18&quot;&gt;the best dressed man in the NBA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a talk by &lt;a href=&quot;glennadamson.com&quot;&gt;glenn adamson&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glennadamson.com/work/2017/8/2/complexitycomplex&quot;&gt;complexity complex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’m thinking about communalism and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milk_kinship&quot;&gt;milk kinship&lt;/a&gt; is a fascinating example of the embodied politic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Noble offspring were often sent to milk kin fosterers that would foster them to maturity so that the children would be raised by their successive status subordinates. The purpose of this was for political importance to build milk kin as bodyguards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2017/06/corporate-mentorship-programs/528927/&quot;&gt;why doesn’t mentoring work?&lt;/a&gt; from the atlantic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are many problems with the existing model of corporate mentorship, says Jennifer Labin, the principal partner of TERP Associates, a firm that specializes in creating public- and private-sector mentoring programs. “Mentoring programs have become this band-aid,” Labin says. She adds that, in her experience, programs are often “thrown together by overworked, overwhelmed people who’ve never built mentoring programs.” Many people in these roles have often never even been mentored themselves, according to Labin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the book Intelligent Mentoring, by Audrey Murrell, Sheila Forte-Trammel, and Diana Bing, the authors assert that the more traditional approach to mentoring—in which an older (and often white and male) senior employee chooses a younger (and often white and male) protégé to take beneath his wing—is outdated. The main reason this is the case is that one-on-one mentoring was pioneered during a time when it was normal for people to stay in the same full-time job, at the same organization, for years—if not their entire career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Researchers have established that negative mentoring experiences caused more intense emotional and behavioral responses among employees compared to positive incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…it’s hard to fix mentoring programs if employers don’t ask for feedback and employees don’t tell them what’s wrong. And that may be the case in many places. When I reached out to a group of elite, professional women about their experiences with workplace-based mentoring, hardly anyone volunteered to share stories on the record, for fear of professional blowback. One woman simply wrote, “Try to avoid formal programs at all costs. Torture.” The key to creating better mentorship programs, Labin said, is to be more thoughtful in the planning stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kanye’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=myrXQebr488&quot;&gt;original beat tape&lt;/a&gt; and a song from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IF_8zQYw24w&quot;&gt;Drake’s Dad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;long read on &lt;a href=&quot;https://longreads.com/2018/03/27/the-death-row-book-club/&quot;&gt;the death row book club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">i went for a walk in holland and i hope to go on this 2800 mile walk in england soon… i realized on my walk that walking is so fundamentally human that to leave it out of our rituals is to deprive ourselves of our selves.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">fool’s errand</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/fools-errand/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="fool's errand" /><published>2018-04-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/fools-errand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/fools-errand/">&lt;p&gt;really thinking hard about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dark-mountain.net/about/manifesto/&quot;&gt;dark mountain manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. it’s almost a decade old but still unfortunately prescient:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… a simple fact which any historian could confirm: human civilisation is an intensely fragile construction. It is built on little more than belief: belief in the rightness of its values; belief in the strength of its system of law and order; belief in its currency; above all, perhaps, belief in its future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is the story of how that people will cope with the crumbling of their own myth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Integrity is wholeness, the greatest beauty is / Organic wholeness, the wholeness of life and things, the divine beauty / of the universe. Love that, not man / Apart from that, or else you will share man’s pitiful confusions, / or drown in despair when his days darken.
– Robinson Jeffers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is not a rejection of our humanity — it is an affirmation of the wonder of what it means to be truly human. It is to accept the world for what it is and to make our home here, rather than dreaming of relocating to the stars, or existing in a Man-forged bubble and pretending to ourselves that there is nothing outside it to which we have any connection at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The big names of contemporary literature are equally at home in the fashionable quarters of London or New York, and their writing reflects the prejudices of the placeless, transnational elite to which they belong.The converse also applies. Those voices which tell other stories tend to be rooted in a sense of place. Think of John Berger’s novels and essays from the Haute Savoie, or the depths explored by Alan Garner within a day’s walk of his birthplace in Cheshire. Think of Wendell Berry or WS Merwin, Mary Oliver or Cormac McCarthy. Those whose writings approach the shores of the Uncivilised are those who know their place, in the physical sense, and who remain wary of the siren cries of metrovincial fashion and civilised excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;nutrifluff&lt;/em&gt; is my new favorite word: nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2018/mar/25/chocolate-the-dark-truth-is-it-good-for-you-health-wellbeing-blood-pressure-flavanols&quot;&gt;Guardian article about chocolate&lt;/a&gt; that holds a larger message about the fragility of science and marketing. especially meta since this one word, ‘nutrifluff’, was picked up by dozens of online news-hawkers…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/22/t-magazine/art/artist-day-job.html&quot;&gt;artists and their day jobs&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It is not two jobs at all… one rests the man when the other fatigues him.” – William Carlos Williams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(After all, who wants to spend all their time in one room, even if it belongs to them?) Sometimes the artist needs to turn off, to get out in the fray, to stop worrying over when her imagination’s pot will boil…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;don’t resist and urge, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/your-money/resistance-is-futile-to-change-habits-try-replacement-instead.html&quot;&gt;replace it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;newish movie &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/26/movies/the-square-review-elisabeth-moss.html?referrer=google_kp&quot;&gt;The Square&lt;/a&gt; got me thinking about attention and responsibility in relation to art&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-markoff-stewart-brand-whole-earth-catalog-20180328-story.html&quot;&gt;Whole Earth Catalog turns 50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://semsound.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;friend of mine made a cool poetry app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2013/jan/27/kraftwerk-most-influential-electronic-band-tate&quot;&gt;who is Kraftwerk?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakola.com/arts/jerry-seinfeld-comedian-award-2007&quot;&gt;a funny speech from jerry seinfeld about awards&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And I don’t want to give you the wrong impression. I don’t want you to think that I’m not honored by this, because I’m, I feel very, very honored, and it’s – but it’s just that awards are stupid. Every real estate office has some framed, five-diamond president’s award thing by the desk, every hotel check-in has some gold circle service thing; every car salesman is a platinum jubilee winner. It’s all a big jerk off. It is, the hotel sucks, the real estate person is stupid, and the only thing the car salesman is good at is ripping you off. And why? Because awards don’t mean a goddamn thing. It’s stupid, they’re all stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Turk&quot;&gt;history of the mechanical turk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://abstractions.nautil.us/article/290/the-simple-algorithm-that-ants-use-to-build-bridges&quot;&gt;how ants build bridges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new words:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tate.org.uk/art/art-terms/a/agit-prop&quot;&gt;agitprop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/aetiology&quot;&gt;aetiology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peccadillo&quot;&gt;peccadillo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">really thinking hard about the dark mountain manifesto. it’s almost a decade old but still unfortunately prescient:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">deep result: everything oscillates</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/oscillations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="deep result: everything oscillates" /><published>2018-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/oscillations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/oscillations/">&lt;p&gt;start with a great &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mathematical_jargon#deep&quot;&gt;wiki list of mathematical jargon&lt;/a&gt;, where we find the concept of a “deep result” is explained. a deep result is one which requires “deeper” knowledge, certain latent structures, to prove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;an example of a deep result is the infinite number of primes, which led me to a prime plot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot; height: 200px; overflow: hidden&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/0a/Primes_-_distribution_-_up_to_19_primorial.png/800px-Primes_-_distribution_-_up_to_19_primorial.png&quot; alt=&quot;Drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which looks shockingly similar to a spike raster plot of neurons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://actionpotential.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/polychronization01.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;looking at control systems, I found a reference to an older feedback controller than &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centrifugal_governor&quot;&gt;Maxwell’s steam engine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cornelis_Drebbel#Works&quot;&gt;Cornelius Hebbel’s&lt;/a&gt; temperature-regulating oven for chicken egg incubation. i then found an &lt;strong&gt;even&lt;/strong&gt; older version by the greek &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Water_clock#Greco-Roman_world&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;clepsydra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which means “water-thief”. feedback is used to correct the fact that a fuller pot will outflow from its bottom faster than a less full pot, due to the higher pressure at the outlet. the greeks even had alarms consisting of gongs attached to water clocks. bonkers. say thanks to poor &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ctesibius&quot;&gt;ctesibus&lt;/a&gt; for these wonderful inventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;attending a royal society meeting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://royalsociety.org/science-events-and-lectures/2018/03/natural-systems/&quot;&gt;computation by natural systems&lt;/a&gt;, i was struck by an offhand comment at lunch (accompanied by a characteristic grin) by professor nick monk: “&lt;strong&gt;everything oscillates&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thinking about how the animal controls itself (weaning myself off of thinking about how to control the animal), a series of works by muraven and baumeister:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/buy/1998-01923-011&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/buy/1998-00299-017&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/docview/199849497?pq-origsite=gscholar&quot;&gt;1999&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2000-03444-003&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1467-8721.2007.00534.x&quot;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which all make the claim that cognitive regulation is a muscle that can be strengthened with deliberate effort. looking for normative results, i found a paper laboring towards a mechanistic understanding at this deliberate practice, a personal trainer for your mind-muscle, so to speak. the take-home from all of this work is inhibition; self-control or “executive function”, focused in the prefrontal cortex, is almost entirely negative feedback– inhibition is central to control. it’s what you &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; respond to that matters: attention is ignoring everything you deem unimportant. who decides what’s important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;speaking of oscillations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thing_(listening_device)&quot;&gt;a crazy story of a bug&lt;/a&gt; in the US ambassador’s office in Moscow in the 40s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i read &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_Bullshit&quot;&gt;harry frankfurt’s little book on bullshit&lt;/a&gt; a few years ago, but after hearing about james ladyman, i enjoyed his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=32ZaTKa2IRg&quot;&gt;frankfurt-inspired take on pseudoscience&lt;/a&gt; (warning: hour-long lecture)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my take aways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the ideal science should be self-correcting and aware of dogmatism and hubris (how much we know). appeals to epistemic authorities are necessary and relevant both politically and socially. scientific orthodoxy is the best way we have to generate facts and serve as such an authority. pseudoscience is not inherently non-science, fraud science, nor bad science. these non-science sciences must be properly defined for science-science to be held to task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brembs.net/learning/drosophila/foxp/&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; on operant conditioning vs language acquisition in the fly model… chomsky would not be amused. my take home is that this gene has something to do with different learning conditions, but the implications of “self-learning” and “world-learning” are interesting. that is, how is learning reinforced in light of “i did something” vs “my context was different”? perhaps they are one in the same. unclear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://computergraphics.stackexchange.com/questions/5085/light-intensity-of-an-rgb-value&quot;&gt;color is really complex, both physically and biologically&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a friend of mine just published &lt;a href=&quot;https://press.princeton.edu/titles/11108.html&quot;&gt;a spicy book about curves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;last but not least, a quote from lady gaga:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;you have to go to the broken place in your heart to write songs, like open heart surgery– it’s invasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">start with a great wiki list of mathematical jargon, where we find the concept of a “deep result” is explained. a deep result is one which requires “deeper” knowledge, certain latent structures, to prove.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">how you spend your time</title><link href="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/how-you-spend-your-time/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="how you spend your time" /><published>2018-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/how-you-spend-your-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spewil.github.io/blog/weeklies/how-you-spend-your-time/">&lt;p&gt;two aeon pieces that seem related: an incredible short doc about a horologist (which reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c08i_9gumJs&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; clip of Arvo Pärt), and a take on Martin Buber’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_and_Thou&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I and Thou&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. how can &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt; be loved? is there ever a time, so to speak, to break Buber’s commandment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/videos/finding-chaos-and-precision-in-all-things-a-philosophy-of-watchmaking&quot;&gt;chaos and precision in all things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/all-real-living-is-meeting-the-sacred-love-of-martin-buber&quot;&gt;the sacred love of martin buber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;speaking of things– a story of buildings and strength&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2018/feb/11/roma-agrawal-structural-engineers-are-unsung-heroes-interview-shard&quot;&gt;roma agrawal’s &lt;em&gt;Built&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the OJ trial is still overwhelming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1994/07/25/an-incendiary-defense&quot;&gt;jeffrey toobin’s 1994 &lt;em&gt;An Incendiary Defense&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what better story than a steamship full of refugee Soviet philosophers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philosophers%27_ships&quot;&gt;philosopher’s ships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there’s an inexplicable, visual beauty in the geometry and topology of music&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@lucas_gonze/coltrane-pitch-diagrams-e25b7d9f5093&quot;&gt;coltrane’s pitch diagrams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the relationship between wartime and technology never ceases to astound and frighten me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/1945/07/as-we-may-think/303881/&quot;&gt;as we may think, 1945&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vannevar_Bush&quot;&gt;vannevar bush&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;brushes, paints and the marks of self. bacon’s digestion/regurgitation of subjectivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MgrO5za0lSY&quot;&gt;a brush with violence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wonderful essay from Ramachandran about the self&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edge.org/conversation/self-awareness-the-last-frontier&quot;&gt;self: the last frontier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">two aeon pieces that seem related: an incredible short doc about a horologist (which reminds me of this clip of Arvo Pärt), and a take on Martin Buber’s I and Thou. how can things be loved? is there ever a time, so to speak, to break Buber’s commandment?</summary></entry></feed>